This story is fiction. The names of people,
places and groups are imaginary.
Obey traffic rules and drive safely.
Initial
Raise up your hands 高く [Everybody gonna tell you I can't stop]
Raise up your hands takaku
(Everybody now te wo agero saa)
Tsukame brand new tomorrow
掴め Brand new tomorrow [You don't stop]
(You don't stop)
風の中で 自分を知る ずっと最高のDreamだろう
Kaze no naka de jibun wo shiru
Zutto zekkei no dream darou
(Let's go)
Oh[Let's go] Oh[Let's go]
Oh
Oh (Let's go)
Oh raise up you can't stop
Oh, raise up your hands now.
Ikiteru dake de marumouke nara ganbarouze marugoto ittennbari
生きてるだけで何やろうかな
Gamble on 迫る鼓動にテンバリ
同じMission 同じ一生
Onaji mission, onaji isshou
Dondake yume atsuika ga shobu darou
どんだけ夢熱いかが勝負だろ
Escalator nashi no eien
Escalator 無しの永遠
Ashi koshi kitae reruze yeah, yeah
足腰鍛え Let's begin yeah
Douse noboru kaidan
どうせのぼる階段
心こっちにCustomizeしちゃえばいい
Kokoro kocchi ni customize shichaeba ii
Kezurarete sugiru mainichi
削られて 過ぎる毎日[But you know]
Kezurarete sugiru mainichi (But you know ?)
攻めがいのあるGameと 笑い飛ばして
Semegai no aru game to warai tobashite
Let's see how fast you can do it
Let's see how fast you can do it.
Raise up your hands ずっと [Everybody gonna tell you I can't stop]
Raise up your hands zutto
(Everybody now te wo agero saa)
Hashire sleepless challenger
走れ Sleepless challenger [You don't stop]
(You don't stop)
今に生きる 理由を探す
Ima ni ikiru riyuu sagasu
Yume tsukinai quest
夢尽きないQuest
(Let's go)
Oh[Let's go] Oh[Let's go]
Oh
Oh (Let's go)
Oh, raise up your hands now.
Oh raise up you can't stop
遥々来たぜ
I've come all the way to Kanagawa !
神奈川へ
宿命のライバル藤原拓海に送れること一ヶ月半
One and a half months behind
his arch rival, Fujiwara Takumi...
...Takeuchi Itsuki finally steps
into the land of Hakone !
武内樹　箱根の地に立つ
意味合いがまったく違う
You got it completely wrong.
You're just a sightseer.
お前はただの観光客だろう
売店のおばちゃんが言ってたんだけど
The woman at the kiosk told me that it's rare
to see Mt. Fuji so clearly at this time of year.
この時季にこんだけ綺麗に富士山が見えるのは珍しいんだってさ
それって何かいいことが起こるって事か
Does this mean something good will happen ?
当然っすよ
It should ! Today is Project D's
final battle in Kanagawa !
なんたって今日はプロジェクトDの神奈川最終戦っすからね
これで　拓海の勝利は間違い無し
Takumi's victory is guaranteed !
そう簡単に行けばいいがな
I hope it's that simple.
よ　誰かと思えば
Oh, I thought I recognized that voice.
妙義ナイトキッズの中里さんに庄司さん
Nakazato and Shoji
of the Myogi Night Kids...?!
多分来てるんだろうなと思ってたよ
I knew you guys would be here
because this is the final race.
フィナーレだしな
そっちこそ　わざわざ来てくれたんっすか
It's great that you came
all the way to support us.
なんだよその言い方
You know, that sounds really disturbing.
引っかかるな
藤原拓海を自分たちだけの代表みたいに言うなよ
Don't think of Fujiwara Takumi as
the representative of your team only.
プロジェクトDは群馬エリアみんなの期待を背負ってんだ
Project D carries the hopes
of everyone in the Gunma area.
こうしてこのデッキから富士山を見るのも
So today is the last day we
get to see Mt. Fuji from this deck.
今日で最後って事か
何か今でもこの状況が信じられないな
I still can't believe the situation I'm in.
プロジェクトDのメンバーでいることが不思議ですよ
It still feels weird that
I'm a member of Project D.
そうだぜ
You might as well thank me.
お前俺に感謝しろよ
I went all the way to Akina to invite you.
俺様が直々に秋名まで声かけに行ってやったんだからな
そうでしたね
Yeah, you did.
にやけてんじゃねえって
Wipe that look off.
絶対に負けんなよ
Don't lose.
今回のお前の相手
I haven't seen your opponent yet,
but I sense something really bad.
姿は見てないが
ヤバそうなムードがビンビンだぜ
俺の走り屋としての感はあたる
My intuition as a street racer is usually correct.
たぶん　幽霊みたいな奴だ
Your opponent must be like a ghost, and you'll have a tough time.
めっちゃ苦戦する
マジで
Seriously ?!
けど　負けるとは思わない
But I don't think you'll lose.
I'm saying it because you were like a ghost before, but now I can see you.
何故ならお前も昔は幽霊だったが
今は足がある
だから　負けないよ
So you won't lose.
絶対に勝ち抜こうぜ
We've gotta win.
向こうがデータ重視なら
If they're focused on the data, we just
have to be better than we are now.
俺たちは今までの俺たちを超えればいい
Brothers
いいお天気だね
Great day, isn't it ?
見て見て
Look, the surface of
Ashino Lake shines like a mirror.
芦ノ湖の湖面が鏡みたいじゃない
久しぶりに真子に会えたわけだし
I haven't seen you for a while.
I want to enjoy the hot spring
and drink tonight. It'll be fun.
今夜は温泉浸かってお酒でも飲んで
盛り上がりたいね
何言ってるの沙雪
What are you talking about, Sayuki ? We don't have time for that tonight.
今夜はそれどころじゃないでしょう
分かってるよ　冗談でしょう
I know. I was joking.
I've come all the way from Karuizawa
to root for the cute Takumi.
あたしだってわざわざ軽井沢から
可愛い拓海くんの応援に来たんだから
どんだけ成長していい男になったか楽しみだよ
I'm looking forward to seeing
how handsome he has become.
それより真子　レースの方はどうなのさ
That aside, how're you
doing in the races ?
It's tough.
大変だよ
I hate to admit it, but I'm always blown away by the level of those around me.
悔しいけど　周りのレベルの高さにいつもとまどっているの
自分がレースをかじるようになって
After I started racing, I realized
how great professional drivers are.
プロのドライバーの凄さが身にしみてるから
プロジェクトDの戦績は信じられないって言うか
Project D's achievement
is incredible, almost divine.
神がかりだよ
何人も負けてるもんね　プロが
A lot of pros have been defeated.
でも今回は今までのようには行かないかも
It might be different this time around.
Sidewinder has a professional manager.
サイドワインダーはマネージメントのプロがいるし
沙雪は知らないと思うけど
You might not know this, but this event has
caught the attention of people from all sides.
いろんな方面からの注目度がすごいの
If they win, it will cause a stir.
これでもし勝つような事があれば
ホントに大変だよ
公道の走り屋たちの
This might not end as a mere carnival among a small group of street racers.
狭い世界だけのカーニバルでは終わらないかも
厳しい戦いに成るかな
Is this battle going to be tough ?
まあね
Probably so.
Kubo Eiji's bio is very interesting.
久保英次という男の経歴がなかなか面白いんだ
He used to work at the racing
division of a large manufacturer...
元々は大手のメーカー系レース部門で働いていた人物だけど
数年前に独立して自分のショップを経営している
...but he left the company a few years ago, and now he manages his own shop.
デモカーを作ってサーキットでタイムアタックをしながら
He develops aftermarket parts while he builds demo cars to compete for times in the circuits.
アフターパーツの開発をしている
彼が作ったパーツは性能がいいことで定評があるんだ
His parts are known for
their high performance.
正にプロだな
He's a real pro.
ユニークなのはラリーをやっていて
What's unique is that he used to compete in rallying, and even won some big prizes in provincial races.
地方の大会で上位に入賞した経歴があるんだ
そりゃ手強いな
He sounds tough, the circuit part really creates an almighty air about him.
サーキットだけでなくオールマイティな感じが
そういう事さ
You're right.
By the way, Fumihiro...
ところで　史浩
今日のパスタ　なに
What's today's pasta ?
頼むよ　お願いだから
I beg you, please.
Can you call and cancel the event ?
母さんから電話して　今度の事断ってくれない
今更そんな事出来ないでしょう
You can't do that any more.
どうしても行くのがイヤなら
If you really don't want to do it,
you should call Hojo yourself.
自分で北条さんに電話しなさい
無理だよ　あの人怖いし
That's impossible. He's scary.
子供みたいな事言ってんじゃないの
Stop talking like a little child.
やると言った事には責任を持ちなさい
You said you'd do it, so be
responsible for what you said.
何か気が重いんだよ
I don't feel like it.
And there's a show I want to watch, too.
見たいテレビだってあるし
まさか　怖くなったの
Are you scared ?
I've never felt fear, but
this is too much of a bother.
怖いなんて思ったことないけど
めんどくさいのやなんだよ
車で競争することの意味だって分かんないし
I don't understand the
meaning of racing cars.
そんな事に何の価値があるっていうの
What's the point ?
それは貴方が直接北条さんに尋ねなさい
You should ask Hojo yourself.
走るにしても走らないにしても
Whether you drive or not,
you're obligated to see Hojo on time.
シンちゃんは約束の時間に北条さんの所に行く義務があるのよ
It's like they're glued together.
ベタベタしやがって
俺から見ればお前らキモイんだ
From where I stand
you're just plain creepy
いくら仲が良くても
No matter how close you are, that won't bring you victory. I'll let you know that.
そんなんじゃ勝てねーって事を思い知らせてやる
北条はん
Hojo...
...I've finished my data
collection and analysis.
最終的なデータの集積と解析　終わりました
神奈川の三戦と昨日のプラクティスで集めたデータで
I think I know the combat potential of the FD, based on the data from the first three races in Kanagawa and last night's practice.
向こうのFDの戦闘力はほぼ把握できたと思います
それにそってNSXのセッティングも完了
Your NSX's settings have
been completed accordingly.
NAミッドシップの利点を最大限に活かしましょう
Let's take advantage of the
NA engine and mid-ship layout.
Traction is everything in hill-climbing.
ヒルクライムはトラクションが全てです
コーナーの出口で踏んだ時
The key is how efficiently the car can transfer
its power to the ground at the exit of each corner.
いかにパワーを無駄なく路面に伝えるかが勝負です
If you can gain a 0.1 second advantage in one section, you can gain a 1 second advantage in ten sections.
一つの区間でコンマ一秒稼げれば
十個で立派に一秒の差に成るわけですから
Motorsports are plain and simple...
モータースポーツっちゅうのは身も蓋もなく物理ですわ
It's all about physics, although
I don't have to explain it to you now.
もっともそんな事は今更説明するまでもないことですが
結論から言いましょう
Let me get to the point.
同じ力量のドライバーが同じ条件で走らせたと仮定して
Based on the assumption of using the
same driver in the same environment...
十五秒のアドバンテージを作りました
...your car should have a 15 second advantage.
15 seconds is not a big advantage
for the entire distance of the course.
このコースで15秒というのは
決して大きなアドバンテージとは言えません
向こうのFDが想定より
Their FD is far more refined than expected, which is my miscalculation, but...
遥かに素晴らしい仕上がりだったのは誤算でしたが
...I did my best under the given circumstances.
これでも与えられた条件でベストは尽くしたつもりです
You aren't satisfied with
only 15 seconds, are you ?
不満ですかな　15秒では
It's enough.
Who do you think I am, Kubo ?
十分だ
俺は誰だと思ってる　久保さん
群馬から来たヤンキーあがりにドライビングで負けると思うか
Do you think I'll lose to some punk
from Gunma in driving technique ?
群馬から来たヤンキーあがりは侮れませんね
You can't make light
of the punk from Gunma.
15秒のアドバンテージも使い方を間違えば足すくわれます
If you fail to use that 15 second
advantage properly, you might get screwed.
すげー　フリー走行なのに　鳥肌立った
Cool !
Even though it's only free practice,
it still gave me goose bumps.
あんなのと戦わなくちゃいけないのか　高橋啓介は
Takahashi Keisuke is going
to race against that monster ?
どうです　北条はん
How is it, Hojo ?
いいね　上々だ
Pretty good. Well done.
久保さん
Mr. Kubo !
なんやて　乾が来てない
What ? Inui hasn't come yet ?
母親に電話したんですが
I called his mother, and found out
that he left home a while ago.
とっくに家は出ているそうです
登校拒否ならぬ出走拒否か
It's like he's playing hooky,
not from school, but from racing ?
どうします
What should we do ? Should we
arrange a substitute for the downhill ?
念のため　ダウンヒルの代役をたてとおきましょうか
それをしてくれ
Do that, but only as insurance.
だがあくまで念のためや
ギリギリまで　乾を待つ
We'll wait for Inui until the last moment.
Chickening out right when it counts...
いざという時にひよりやがって
What a brat.
困ったガキだぜ
I think he's out there
somewhere wondering what to do.
今頃どこかで一人迷ってると思います
ダウンヒルのスタートまでには腹を決めて現われるでしょう
I'm sure he'll make up his mind and
show up before the downhill race starts.
だといいがな
I hope so.
箱根の山にはもう現れないんじゃなかったのか
I thought you'd never
show up in Hakone again.
死神GTRはもういない
The Grim Reaper GT-R is
no more, but I'm still alive.
だが俺は生きている
自分が行きたいと思った所には行く
I'll go wherever I want to.
こうして話すのもずいぶん久しぶりだな
We haven't talked like this in a while.
すまなかったな　豪
I'm sorry, Gou.
お前にもオヤジたちにも迷惑を掛けてしまった
I've caused a lot of problems
for you and our father.
兄貴　何をしに来たんだ
Brother, why did you come here ?
お前の走りを見にな
To watch your driving.
いけなかったか
You got a problem with that ?
昔のようにアドバイスをするつもりはない
I'm not going to give you
any advice like I did before.
優秀な参謀がついている事だしな
You have a great strategist anyway.
There's just one thing...
ただ　一言だけ
涼介はデカイぜ
Ryosuke is big.
お前はラッキーだ
You're fortunate.
車と峠を愛する物としてこれほどの幸せはないだろ
As a man who loves cars and mountain passes, you can't be happier than this.
できる最高の走りをしろ
Do your very best.
Use everything you've learned.
今まで培って来たものを全て出し切ってみろ
そして楽しめ
And enjoy yourself.
This time, I'll watch you until the end.
こんどこそ最後まで見届けてやる
そろそろスタートする頃だ
It's about to start.
見物だな
This hill-climb is going to be good.
このヒルクライムは
先何か話しかけていただろう　弟に
You were talking to your
little brother a while ago.
What kind of advice did you give him ?
どんなアドバイスをした
I didn't give him anything of the sort.
そんな物はしていない
重たいものを背中から下ろしてやっただけだ
I just removed a heavy burden from his back.
ネガティブな感情をモチベーションにして走っても
You can't perform well by using
negative emotions as motivation.
いいパフォーマンスは出せない
I just figured he wouldn't be able to defeat Ryosuke's little brother in that condition.
そんな状態では　涼介の弟には勝てない気がしてな
なるほど　俺の理論でも
I see.
My Zero Theory has a similar rule,
which is to get rid of all negative emotions.
ネガティブな感情は全て排除するのがルールだ
怒り　嫉み　恨み　虚栄心
Anger, jealousy, grudge, self-glory, and sadness...
そして悲しみ
そう言った負の感情はドライバーを正しくは導かない
Those negative emotions will not
guide a driver in the right direction.
プロジェクトDが何故あれほど強いか分かるか
Do you know why Project D is so strong ?
They always look like they're having fun.
あいつらはどんな時でも楽しそうなんだ
車が好きで　峠が好きでここまで走ってきた
They love cars and mountain passes.
That's what drove them until now.
どんなピンチに立たされてもそれをどこかで楽しんでしまう
No matter how difficult the situation becomes,
they somehow find a reason to enjoy it.
それに対して迎え撃つ神奈川陣営は楽しめていない
On the other hand, Kanagawa
drivers aren't enjoying this at all...
...because their sensibility
and pride get in the way.
意地とプライドは邪魔をするんだ
絶対に負けられないと思った瞬間に苦しくなる
You corner yourself the moment you think there's no way you can lose.
楽しんでしまえばいい
You've got to have fun.
勝ち負けでなく
Rather than winning or losing, it's a matter of whether you can enjoy this or not...
楽しめるかどうかに意味がある
特に今日はカーニバルの最終日だからな
...especially because today is
the final day of the carnival.
スタート五秒前
Five seconds to the start.
4　3　2　1
Four...
Three...
Two...
One...
Go !
ゴー
Here they come.
来るぞ　来るぞ
Incredible.
すっげー
The NSX looks much more
aggressive than during practice.
プラクティスの時と迫力が違う
ベッタリと低くてホントにスーパーカーだ
It hugs the road like a real supercar
見てるこっちが怖くなるよ
Watching it gives me chills.
Plus, it's in the front position, which means the
FD has no chance of winning if the race drags on.
しかも先行だぜ
消耗戦になったら
百パーセントFDに勝ち目はない
しっくり来ねえな
I don't like his lack of focus.
この焦点がボヤけた感じ
何を考えている
What's on your mind ?
I see your hesitation from behind.
背中に迷いが見えるぜ
兄貴　ドタン場に来てそれはないぜ
Brother, you can't show up
and spout such nonsense.
俺が今どういう立場でいるか分かってるだろう
You know what my responsibilities are.
何や何でも勝つつもりで準備をしてきた
I did everything in
preparation to win this race.
モチベーションは十分高かったんだ
My motivation was high enough.
それだけではダメだと言いたいのか
But you still think it's not enough ?
俺は絶対に負けたくない
I don't want to lose no matter what...
何が言いたかったんだ　兄貴
...so what were you trying to say, Brother ?
罪作りなことを言ったんじゃないか
You could have jinxed him.
豪君にアンタの真意が伝わっているかな
I wonder if Gou will
understand your true intentions.
モチベーションの質はともかく
Regardless of his motivation,
I still don't think Sidewider will lose.
サイドワインダーが負けるとは思わないね
十分に時間を掛けて勝つための準備をしてきているんだ
They spent enough time on
preparations in order to win.
久保英次という参謀もいることだしな
They have a strategist named Kubo Eiji.
Kubo, huh ?
久保か
あんなメタボおやじはクソだ
That old fart stinks.
セコイだけで涼介に比べて美学がない
He's just sneaky, nothing like Ryosuke, who has aesthetic quality.
なるほど
I see. That sounds more
like the Hojo Rin I know.
それでこそ　俺が知っている北条凛だ
Gou might be confused for a
short period of time, but he'll get it.
一時的には混乱するだろうが
豪なら分かるはずだ
まずは空っぽになることだ
First, he has to empty his mind...
本当に重要な事を思い出すためにな
...so that he can recall what's truly important.
大宮さん
Omiya, what kind of driver is Hojo of Sidewinder ?
サイドワインダーの北条って
どんなドライバーなんですか
兄の凛なら知ってるが
I know Rin, the older brother...
弟の豪とは直接サーキットでやり合ったことはないんだ
...but I've never competed in the circuit
against Gou, because he's much younger.
世代がかなり下だから
走行会では　北条兄弟と言えば
The Hojo Brothers are pretty
well-known on the circuit.
知られた存在だった
兄の凛がラインを見せながら
I remember the older Rin always guided his
younger brother by showing him the ideal lines.
いつも弟を引っ張っていたのは覚えているよ
仲の良い兄弟だった
They seemed to like each other,
and were exceptionally fast to boot.
ずば抜けて速かったしな
なんとなく似ているっていうか　かぶりますよね
They're very similar in some aspects to the Takahashi Brothers of Project D.
プロジェクトDの高橋兄弟に
クールで理論派の兄と感情派の弟と
The cool-headed and logical older brother and the emotional younger brother...
似ているかもしれないな
You can say they are alike,
especially the younger brothers.
特に弟の二人は
コントロールの幅の狭いピーキーな車を操り
They both drive a peaky car with a narrow margin of control, and they compete in cornering speed.
コーナーワックの速さでの勝負
どちらも集中力と瞬発力が信条だからな
Concentration and mad-dash
speed are their strengths.
スプリント勝負に成るのは必至
This will undoubtedly become a sprint race.
先行した方が　必ずどこかでスパートを掛けてくる
The car in the lead will
make a dash at some point.
二番ヘアピンは今通過したところです
They just passed the second hairpin.
The second hairpin, huh ?
二番ヘアピンか
ここからの第二区間は
From there, section 2 is a mid-speed stage where the cornering speed is slow.
勾配が緩やかで　コーナーの旋回時間も短い
中速セクションに入ります
Section 4, which is between
two hairpin curves, is similar...
さらに
ヘアピンを二個挿んでの第四区間も似たようなステージで
...so section 2 and 4 are where
the NSX will perform better.
第二と第四がNSXの最も得意とするセクションでしょう
区間タイムを見ても
It has a clear advantage in terms of section time.
他の車に対して明らかにアドバンテージが在ります
ミッドシップ故のブレーキの良さと
That's because of better braking due to the mid-ship layout, and the NA engine's immediate response.
NAエンジンの付きの良さがその理由や
勝負に行くならまず第二区間
The first key point is section 2.
If we can surprise the FD driver
by picking up the pace there...
ここでペース上げてFDを慌てさせられれば
相手は追従するだけでタイヤを痛めつけることになる
...he'll wear down his tires
just trying to catch up.
ターボに比べてNAはタイヤの負担が少ないですからね
NA cars are easier on tires,
compared to turbo-charged cars.
If we hold on until section 4
and launch a full attack...
第四まで引っ張って渾身のフルアッタクをかければ
後輪駆動ターボのFDでは
...the rear-wheel drive, turbo-charged FD won't be able to keep up.
とうてい持ち堪えられないでしょう
Given the fact that Hojo chose the front position, that must be his scenario.
一本目先行選んだからには　それが北条はんのシナリオやろ
バトルが動くのはここからやね
The battle will take a new turn from there.
言う事が分からないぜ
I don't understand...
楽しいだけで走っていられたのはもう昔の話だ
We used to drive just for fun,
but that was a long time ago.
There's something strange
about my brother now.
兄貴は何かがずれてるんじゃないのか
あれこれ考えるのは止めた
I'd better stop thinking so hard.
I just have to show
how fast I normally drive...
俺はいつものように自分の速さを見せつけるだけだ
...with this car.
この車で
キレがよくなってきやがった
He's started to show sharper movements.
何か嫌な感じだぜ
I don't like this.
こっちがミスをしたわけじゃないのに
He suddenly pulls away even
if I don't make any mistakes...
ホント差が開く
兄貴が予言してたとおりだ
...which is exactly what my brother predicted.
He gives off the same
feeling as a certain someone.
この感じ　ちょっとあいつに似ている
気持ちの準備が無かったら　きっと慌てていただろ
I'd be panicked if I hadn't anticipated this.
けどまだ　本気の勝負はここじゃねえ
But this isn't where the real battle takes place.
NSXの早い感覚には　少なからず戸惑うですよね
He might be shocked by
the NSX's speed more or less.
The hill-climb of this vehicle class was
always fought between turbo-charged cars.
このクラスのヒルクライムともなれば
どんな時でもターボ対ターボという構図でしたから
国産のスポーツカーでは
The NSX is the only exception, as far as domestic sports cars are concerned.
NSXだけが唯一の例外だからな
贅沢にコストのかかった大排気量のNAを
The expensive and large engine is
mounted in the middle of the chassis...
シャシーの中心にドッカリとマウントさせて
インフィールドでのスピードはターボにはないキレがある
...which gives the car superb
handling on a twisty course.
ミッドシップ故のコーナーリングスピードの高さと
The high cornering speed
of the mid-ship layout...
NAエンジンのリニア特性からくる脱出速度の高さ
...and the fast cornering exit speed
of the NA engine's linear response.
The butt-kicking acceleration of the NA engine will become even handier on public roads...
アクセルを踏んだ瞬間
背中を蹴飛ばさてるあのNAの加速感は
細かいコーナーの多い公道ステージでは
...with so many more short
corners than circuits have.
サーキット以上に有利だろう
But I don't think he's upset...
だけど　あいつは慌ててはいないさ
身近にもいたからな
...because he's familiar with the type of driver who has a unique style of using the NA engine's advantage.
NAの特性を生かして
独自のゾーンで走るドライバーが
You mean Fujiwara ?
藤原のことですか
北条豪のNSXは
I think Hojo Gou's NSX driving
style is similar to Fujiwara's.
藤原のゾーンと似たような走り方をするんじゃないかと俺は思う
ダウンヒルでなく
If you adapt that type
of driving to the hill-climb...
ヒルクライムに置き換えてイメージしていけば
やり辛い相手ですね
That's a difficult opponent to deal with.
そうには違いないが
That's true.
But I knew early on that our
opponent would be using an NSX.
相手がNSXであることは
早い段階でキャッチしていたし
俺も啓介もなんの準備もせずに
It's not like Keisuke and I just
sat back and waited for today.
今日を迎えたわけじゃない
こっちにも切り札はある
We have our own trump card.
Keisuke, use all the skills you've
learned up until today in this race.
啓介　今まで培ってきた物を
全て出して戦うんだ
分からない　この人達は何を期待して
I don't get it.
What did they come here for ?
こんな所に集まってるんだ
あんな女の人まで
Even women like them.
こんな場所に似合わない気がする
It's odd to see someone like
them in a place like this.
What should I do ?
僕はどうしたらいいんだ
もう今更ノコノコと出ていけないよ
I can't just show up like nothing's happened.
約束の時間はとっくに過ぎてるし
The meeting time is long past.
But I can't go home either.
でも家にも帰れない
北条さんより　母さんのほうが怒ってる
Mom would be angrier than Hojo.
なんで僕はいつもこうなんだろ
Why am I always like this, running away at the most critical moment and disappointing Mom ?
大事なときにいつも逃げて　母さんをがっかりさせる
でも　一番がっかりしてるのは
But the person who's most disappointed is...
よー　少年
Hey, young man !
どうしたの　暗いよ　君
What's the matter ?
You look so gloomy.
いっ　いいえ　別に　何でもないですけど
Well, um...nothing really.
そう　先から下むいてため息ついてばっかじゃん
Really ?
You've been looking down and
sighing for quite some time.
You look like you're a high school
student. Do you love cars ?
見たところまだ高校生くらいじゃない
クルマ好きなの
Did you come here to see the battle ?
バトル見に来たんでしょう
いいや　好きってわけじゃないですけど
It's not that I love them,
but I feel like I do more or less...
なっ　なんとなく
なんとなくか　まぁ　いいか
More or less, huh ? Oh, whatever.
あたしは沙雪で
I'm Sayuki.
こっちのエロいお姉さんは真子　君は
This sexy lady is Mako.
What's your name ?
信司です　乾信司
Shinji...Inui Shinji.
今　三番ヘアピンを通過しました
They just passed the third hairpin.
区間タイムもでました
I have their section time.
Looks like their pace has increased.
ペース上がってますね
ここまでは予定どおり
So far, it's going as planned.
Good enough.
これでええ
信司くんってここら辺に住んでるの
Shinji, do you live around here ?
Yes.
そうです
うちらは群馬から来たんだよ　遥々ね
We came all the way from Gunma.
すごいっしょ
Amazing, huh ?
Yeah.
でもどうしてそんな遠くからわざわざ見に来るんですか
Why did you come all the
way here just to see a race ?
そっ　そりゃ　元々走り屋だし
Well, that's because we
used to be street racers.
つっか　楽しんだよね　でしょう真子
Besides, it's fun.
Right, Mako ?
そうだね　見てるだけでドキドキしちゃう
Yes, it is.
It's thrilling just to watch, and it's even more fun if you sit behind the steering wheel.
自分でハンドル握れば　もっと楽しいけどね
楽しい
Fun ?
来たぞ
Here they come !
何なの　どうしてそんなに盛り上がるの
Why ? What made them so excited ?
どう見る　真子
What's your take, Mako ?
なんとも言えないけど
Hard to say, but at least
the NSX's traction is impressive.
やっぱりトラクションすごいね　NSX
このコーナー出口かなりの急勾配だけど
The exit of this corner is really steep, but it
accelerated quickly without losing balance.
グラつきもしないで　猛然と加速していった
The FD is at a disadvantage after all,
because its response was one step behind.
FDやっぱ苦しい　ワンテンポ遅れる
北条さんの赤い車　楽しそうなんかじゃない
Hojo's red car wasn't having fun.
But the yellow car was smiling.
でも　黄色車は　笑ってた
展望台のヘアピンを通過
They passed the hairpin at the observatory, and have entered section 4.
第四セクションに入ります
This is where it begins...
ここからやな
始まったか
It's begun.
こっからはもうタイヤ労れねえけど
I can't conserve the tires from here on, but I'm counting on you, my FD.
頼むぜ　FD　踏ん張ってくれよ
Please hold on.
Fujiwara Takumi:
Takahashi Ryosuke:
Takahashi Keisuke:
Hojo Rin:
Hojo Gou:
Ikeda Ryuji:
Omiya Satoshi:
Kubo:
Kobayakawa:
Shinji:
Miki Shinichiro
Koyasu Takehito
Seki Tomokazu
Nakamura Yuichi
Kiuchi Hidenobu
Nakai Kazuya
Tochi Hiroki
Kase Yasuyuki
Hamada Kenji
Abe Atsushi
Yuugure ni kawaranai keshiki
日の暮れに 変わらない景色
Iketani Koichiro:
Takeuchi Itsuki:
Kenji:
Sato Mako:
Sayuki:
Nakazato:
Matsumoto:
Fumihiro:
Shinji's Mother:
Man:
Yao Kazuki
Iwata Mitsuo
Takagi Wataru
Neya Michiko
Kakazu Yumi
Hiyama Shinji
Nishi Rintaro
Hosoi Hajime
Hirose Yuka
Takahashi Ryokichi
Furikaeru tadottekita michi
振り返る 辿ってきた道
Setsunasa mo, yorokobi mo, kienai itami mo
切なさも 喜びも 消えない痛みも
Kazoetetara kiri ga nai ne to hitori aruku
数えてたら限がないねと独り歩く
A
Central Anime
Production
Translation:
Hiro-kun
Timing:
Todd Perkins
Editing:
Lillian-Hime
Barbara
Todd Perkins
Brain
Dave
Mouse
Steve S.
Nomake
Kazoekirenai hodo no zanzo
数え切れないほどの残像 ギャンブル生き抜いてきた残党
Gambaru ikinuite kita zattou
Toki ni tatakai toki ni wakari ai
時に戦い 時に解りあい きれい事ばかりじゃなかった真実
Kireigoto bakari ja nakatta shinjitsu
Shotta mama arata na ippo
背負ったまま新たな一歩
Akane gumo ga machi wo someru
あかね雲が街を染める この行く先をそっと問いかけて見る
Kono yuku saki wo sotto toitakete miru
空はなにもいわず だけど私にこの道を照らしている
Sora wa nani mo iwazu
Dakedo watashi ni kono michi wo terashiteiru
透き通る景色を感じて
Sukitooru keshiki wo kanjite
Senritsu wo yuuhi ga kanadete
旋律を夕陽が奏で
Sukitooru keshiki wo kanjite
透き通る景色を感じて
Senritsu wo yuuhi ga kanadete
旋律を夕陽が奏で